spotahome.com 2019-10-30

# Privacy Policies

## **Privacy Policy of www.Spotahome.com**

In compliance with the provisions of Constitutional Law 15/99, of 13 December, on the Protection of Personal Data, and Regulation (EU) 2016/679, of the European Parliament and of the Council, of 27 April 2016 (hereinafter, the RGPD), we hereby inform you that the personal data communicated will be incorporated into a Database owned by:

_**SPOTAHOME, S.L. (hereinafter, SPOTAHOME), holder of CIF [Tax ID Code] No.: B-87004511, postal address: C/ Vizcaya, 12, 28045 – Madrid - Spain, telephone +34 911 23 28 73 and email: privacy@spotahome.com.**_

For any matter related to SPOTAHOME's processing of the data of natural persons, you can contact our Data Protection Delegate at the following email address **privacy@spotahome.com** SPOTAHOME will collect the following data provided by the User:

**CHAT** : used to assist those asking questions related to SPOTAHOME services. The data of unregistered users that are received in this way are not reused.

  * **Data collected** : email.

  * **Purpose** : to respond to requests for information that the user has made through this channel regarding SPOTAHOME services.

  * **Conservation periods** : the data will be retained until its deletion is requested by the interested party. Once they have been deleted, they will remain blocked for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing thereof.

  * **Justification** : based on the consent given to SPOTAHOME to provide the help requested by non-registered interested parties. Based on the existing legal relationship in the case of registered users.

**CONTACT form** : for addressing queries related to the SPOTAHOME services in their different forms (questions, I am moving to a property, I want to rent a property, collaborators or other matters).

  * **Data collected** : name, surnames, email, subject, message, destination city.
  * **Purpose** : to respond to requests for information that the user has made through this channel regarding SPOTAHOME services.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data will be retained until its deletion is requested by the interested party. Once they have been deleted, they will remain blocked for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing.
  * **Justification** : based on the provision of the consent, SPOTAHOME is entitled to process the data provided by the User through the contact form

**WORK WITH US** : access to recruitment processes or mailing of a SPOTAHOME Curriculum.

  * **Data collected** : professional area, name, surnames, telephone, email, CV, cover letter, other optional information such as presence on social networks, promotional video.
  * **Purpose** : management of the User's candidacy for the published recruitment processes or other vacancies that may arise at SPOTAHOME according to their professional profile.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data will be retained until its deletion is requested by the interested party. Once they have been deleted, they will remain blocked for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing.
  * **Justification** : provision of consent by the User.

**REGISTRATION OF OWNERS/PROPERTIES** : management of registration requests received through different channels from those owners who decide to request the services of SPOTAHOME.

  * **Data collected** : name and surnames, ID number, type of rental (entire house or rooms), address of the property, monthly price, months of deposit, months of minimum stay, telephone, email and number of properties managed. Additionally, the billing information will be provided, as well as the rules and other optional data provided by the owner, such as the means of payment admitted, registration times for entry and exit days, smoking, admission of pets, bill expenses or taxes included in the rental price or other optional preferences. Information on their homes.

  * **Purpose** : to enable the application for the registration of owners, the announcement of their properties on the SPOTAHOME website and the subsequent management by owners of their portfolios and contracts.

  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Assignee** : After the acceptance of the reservations by the owner, we shall transfer your contact details to the tenant.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data shall be retained for the time necessary for the provision of the service or until you request its deletion. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing. 

**TENANT REGISTRATION** : this enables registration on the SPOTAHOME platform by using the Google or Facebook login details.

  * **Data collected** : the registration and profile data that were previously registered with Google and/or Facebook.
  * **Purpose** : the registration of users seeking housing.
  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Assignee** : we shall provide your details to the owners of the homes that you reserve.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data will be retained until we find you the house you are looking for or until you request their removal. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing.

**RESERVATION FORM** : to reserve the property you wish to rent.

  * **Data collected** : city, name, surnames, email, telephone, date of birth, sex, nationality, if you are making the move alone or accompanied, where you will work or study. Data for making payment. Optional data: additional information.
  * **Purpose** : help the user to reserve the right home for his/her needs.
  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Assignee** : we shall provide your details to the owners of the homes that you reserve.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data shall be retained until you rent the home you desire or until you request its deletion. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing

**CLIENT BILLING** : management of the billing process with landlords and tenants.

  * **Data collected** : name, surnames, ID or company name, VAT number and bank account number.
  * **Purpose** : manage billing processes with owners and tenants.
  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data shall be retained until the end of the agreement or until you request its deletion. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing. 

**POST BOOKING SERVICE** : for addressing, mediating and resolving possible incidents that may arise during the beginning of the lease contract.

  * **Data collected** : comments, requests or complaints made by SPOTAHOME's own clients.
  * **Purpose** : address, mediate and resolve possible incidents or problems after the lease of the property and to avoid situations of fraud.
  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Assignee** : we will transfer data between owners and tenants for the management of incidents.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data shall be retained until the end of the agreement or until you request its deletion. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing. 

**ASK NICELY** : service designed to assess the degree of satisfaction of owners and tenants during the life of the contract.

  * **Data collected** : name, surnames, email, age, nationality and degree of satisfaction.
  * **Purpose** : to determine the degree of customer satisfaction, address, mediate and resolve possible incidents, problems or bad experiences after the lease of the property.
  * **Justification** : the legal relationship for the provision of the service.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data will be retained until the end of the contractual relationship or until you request its deletion. It will therefore be retained for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and, once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing.

**REVIEWS** : user comments that are published on the website and that aim to evaluate the degree of satisfaction throughout their stay at the property advertised on SPOTAHOME.

  * **Information gathered** : name, age range, and review.
  * **Objective** : to get to know the degree of user satisfaction, and that this may serve as reference for future users. Likewise, they may be shown on the website itself or other promotional materials.
  * **Authorization** : the legal relationship for providing the service.
  * **Held until:** : the data will be held until a request for deletion is made on behalf of the applicant. Once deleted, they will remain blocked for a period of six years at the disposal of public administration, judges, and courts, at the service and defense of the possible liabilities resulting from the process.

**Registration and Monitoring of Corporate Social Network Accounts** : the personal data that you facilitate or provide to social networks when you become a follower. The corporate accounts of SPOTAHOME's social networks are the following:

FACEBOOK: https://www.facebook.com/SpotahomeES TWITTER: https://twitter.com/Spotahome_ES LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/company/spotahome YOUTUBE: https://www.youtube.com/user/spotahome INSTAGRAM: https://www.instagram.com/spotahome_es

  * **Data collected** : name, surnames, email, contact telephone number. 
  * **Purpose** : following social networks and offering promotions and competitions.
  * **Justification** : provision of consent by the User.
  * **Conservation periods** : the data will therefore be kept for the time necessary for the purpose of the processing and once completed, it may be retained for a period of six years at the disposal of the public authorities, judges and courts, for the defence of any possible liabilities arising from the processing.

_Information common to the data collected through the Website mentioned in the previous sections._

**Recipient** : The transfer or communication of data by third parties which provide such services as data-processors is provided for. However, SPOTAHOME must have signed the corresponding Data Processing Agreements with data processors and must have verified that they have sufficient guarantees to apply appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure that the processing is carried out in accordance with the requirements of the RGPD and to guarantee the protection of the interested party's rights.

Specifically, we need to assign or allow access to your personal data, for reasons of service, by the other company of the COKIDOO STUDIOS, S.L.U. business group, as well as other companies that may help us with different issues related to the service. Our suppliers include the following: (i) Companies that provide data processing services; (ii) Companies providing storage services; (iii) Companies that provide services for conducting surveys or market studies; (iv) Authorities or public bodies in the development of their functions. Most of our suppliers are established within the European Economic Area or in countries outside of the European Economic Area but which enjoy the appropriate level of protection in accordance with the provisions of the European Commission. Also, in exceptional cases, we may use suppliers established outside the aforementioned territories, in which case, we make sure that they sign the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission.

We also share certain personal information with third parties who help us to detect and prevent fraudulent transactions. The information we share with those third parties includes some of the information that you share with us (such as, your email address), and some of the information from your online interactions (such as the IP address of your device). That information is used to determine whether a transaction could be fraudulent. One of the third parties we use to help us detect and prevent fraudulent transactions is a UK company called Emailage Limited; they are responsible for their use of your personal information and will use it for the purposes set out in their [privacy policy](https://www.emailage.com/privacy-policy/?utm_source=google&utm_medium=ppc&utm_campaign=brand-awareness).

The user's rights to access, rectification, deletion, limitation, opposition and portability of their data is recognised. Similarly, they have the right to withdraw consent for the processing of data by SPOTAHOME. Likewise, they have the right to file a claim with the supervisory authority.

At any time, the User may exercise their rights by sending a communication, enclosing a document that proves their identity and expressly indicating the right they wish to exercise, to SPOTAHOME at the address indicated above or by sending an email to the address **privacy@spotahome.com**

SPOTAHOME has adopted the necessary technical and organisational measures to guarantee the security and integrity of the data, as well as to avoid its alteration, loss, processing or unauthorised access.

The User expressly accepts the content of the legal notice that regulates the provision of the services.

The data requested on the different forms of the Website are strictly necessary to fulfil its request, and the User communicates them voluntarily. The refusal to provide the data classified as obligatory will lead to the non-provision of the service or the impossibility of accessing the service for which it was requested. Likewise, data may be provided voluntarily with the aim of providing the services in an optimal manner. Similarly, in those cases in which third-party data are provided, the User undertakes to inform them of the content of this [privacy policy](https://www.emailage.com/privacy-policy/?utm_source=google&utm_medium=ppc&utm_campaign=brand-awareness).

The User undertakes to notify SPOTAHOME as soon as possible of any modification or correction of their personal data so that the information contained in the SPOTAHOME Activity Logs is up-to-date at all times.

Based on the legitimate interest of SPOTAHOME, the personal data of the User may be used for the establishment or maintenance of commercial relations via any channel, including electronically, with information of interest regarding SPOTAHOME products and services. The User may at any time oppose such processing for a commercial purpose by sending an email to the address privacy@spotahome.com

Update Date: 24 May 2018 © SPOTAHOME, S.L. 2018 All rights reserved.
